

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







ITIL, Assistant Consultant, Seeking roles in IT Project Mgmt, Production Support, Requirement Gathering, Application Maintenance, Requirement Analysis, Application Support, SQL, XML, PI/sql, Unix Shell Scripting, Oracle, Sybase, DB2, Service Now, Putty, Autosys

Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Designation: Associate Consultant

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services

Current Location: Pune
Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: assistant consultant, team lead/tech lead, it project mgmt, production support, requirement gathering, requirement analysis, application support, sql,xml,pl/sql,unixshell scripting, oracle, sybase, db2, service

now,autosys,itil

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 15-Dec-20 Last Modified: 15-Dec-20

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

11+ Years of experience in the IT industry. 11 Years in application support and Project management for Banking and Financial Project.

Managing a team of 12 people globally, 8 people in Pune, 1 in Singapore,2 in London and 1 in US. Working as Portfolio lead in TCS for barclays capital client, Earlier worked as operation manager of Post Execution Processing Team in TCS for morgan stanley client since Dec 2014 till Dec 2016.

Worked as Onsite Co-ordinator of Post Execution Processing(PEP) in London and Mexico.

Expert in Application Support in Investment Banking & Finance with experience in UNIX, Shell Scripting, DB2 and Sybase technologies.

Have Expertise in Equity and Fixed Income Division for Morgan Stanley. Currently working in Fixed Income Security settlement for Barclays capital.

Strong technical skills, excellent interpersonal communication skills and project management skills, with ability to adapt to new processes and environment proficiently.

I am a PMP aspirant.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as Associate Consultant Feb 2007 to Till Date

production support,portfolio lead

Tata Consultancy Services as Assistant Consultant-Application Support Feb 2007 to Feb 2007

Jan 2017-Till Now (Portfolio Lead-Barclays Capital),Pune
Managing a global team of 12(8 people in Pune , 1 in Singapore,2 in London and 1 in US)
Monitor SLA compliance and review compliance report
Review and Publish Weekly and Monthly operational reviews
Ensure process and service level compliance across levels
Present weekly and Monthly Operational deck.
Team building

Dec. 2014 - Till Dec 2016. (Operations Manager- Morgan Stanley), Pune

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. Role and Responsibilities:-

Managing a global team of 16 (12 in Pune Offshore team + 4 in Mexico Near shore) associates.

Monitor SLA compliance and review compliance report and causal analysis with Service Delivery Manager Review and Publish Weekly and Monthly operational reviews

Schedule and Conduct Monthly Governance reviews

Assist the Shift Lead in ensuring delivery of agreed policies and procedures

Ensure process and service level compliance across levels

Present weekly metrics packs

Review and Analysis the trends and derive the areas of improvement for the team

Competency assessment for Shift Leads

Ensure team have relevant accesses as a part of BCP preparedness

Respond to all service escalations in a timely manner Ensuring capacity management, new application Onboarding and Service Now dashboards are constantly updated.

Shift coverage planning

Oversee management of shifts by Shift Leads and Team Members

Perform random audits to monitor compliance to Operational Procedure Document

Review, Analyse and recommend the automation opportunities with TCS and Morgan Stanley Leads

Team building and evaluation (career planning for resources, performance evaluation, promotion recommendations, motivation)

Accountable for highlighting any service delivery issues to Client management and working with them to resolve them Responsible for attending governance meetings with the Client management and providing periodic status updates Accountable for proper capacity utilization and resource allocations within the team

Aug. 2013 - Nov 2014, Near Shore Deputation in Guadalajara (MEXICO)

Role and Responsibilities:-

Helped in training and setting up a new team in Guadalajara(Mexico), by providing exhaustive training sessions on various applications that the team supports and provided on the job trainings to the new hires.

Interface daily with Front Office and Mddle Office; there is considerable exposure to the trading desks and a key requirement is to build strong user relationships.

Proactive management and monitoring of our environment, together with extensive problem identification, ownership, resolution or escalation.

Managing significant system outages, directing activities of all development and infrastructure teams to resolve serious

Identify improvements to system behaviour, control tools and to monitoring tools.

Monitor SLA compliance and review compliance report and causal analysis with Service Delivery Manager

Review and Publish Weekly and Monthly operational reviews

Knowledge Base: Review & Upload Knowledge Article / Fix-logs in knowledge management tool. Touch base with next level of support for clarifications pertaining to Knowledge Article / Fix-logs/Twikis SNOW Tickets: Accountable for raising SNOW Tickets to support groups by highlighting unclear/ambiguous/incorrect

Knowledge Article / Fix-logs. Track the open SNOW tickets on a daily basis. KMUsage: Accountable for ensuring usage of Knowledge articles by team members during the shift. Carry out weekly

random checks on proper KM usage by team members. Knowledge Article / Fix-log Review. Accountable for ensuring proper Knowledge Article / Fix-log hygiene in existing Knowledge Article / Fix-logs used by the QAPM support team

Feb. 2012 - July 2013, Morgan Stanley, Pune (Operations Manager)

Role and Responsibilities:-

Managing a global team of 12 (9 in Pune Offshore team + 3 in Mexico Near shore) associates.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Physics, Chemistry, Maths.) from Awadesh Pratap Singh University, Rewa in 2002

PG: MCA (Computers) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RCPV), Bhopal in 2006

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
UNIX, Linux, Windows 2007		
C++, C, SQL, XML, sql, pl/sql		
Unix Shell scripting, Oracle 11g, Sybase		
Jira, Twiki, QWEST, Service Now		
Sockeye , Watchtower,Batch mon plus(bmp)		
Putty, Autosys.		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.